Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to another great lesson here at EnglishPod.
欢迎回到 EnglishPod 的另一堂精彩课程。
My name is Marco.
我是 Marco。
And my name is Catherine.
我是 Catherine。
So, Marco, today we've got a little bit of an unusual lesson because we're talking about
那么，Marco，今天我们有一节有点不寻常的课，因为我们要讨论的是
hypothetical situations.
假设的情况。
Right.
对。
We're talking about a unreal situation or something that may happen or may not happen.
我们讨论的是不真实的情况，或者可能发生也可能不会发生的事情。
Okay.
好的。
So, you're going to hear all about this in today's dialogue.
所以，你会在今天的对话中听到所有这些内容。
We're going to hear it a couple of times.
我们会听几遍。
When we come back, we'll be breaking it down for you.
等我们回来，我们会为你详细讲解。
So, you know all about these great phrases and how to talk about not real situations
这样，你就会了解这些很棒的表达，以及如何和朋友们谈论不真实的情况。
with your friends.
和朋友们。
Okay.
好的。
Next question.
下一个问题。
If Eric asked you out on a date, what would you say?
如果 Eric 约你出去约会，你会怎么说？
Duh.
那还用说。
I would say yes.
我会说好。
Eric is the most popular kid in school.
Eric 是学校里最受欢迎的孩子。
Okay.
好的。
My turn.
轮到我了。
What would you do if you won the lottery?
如果你中了彩票，你会做什么？
Let's see.
让我想想。
If I won the lottery, I would buy two tickets for trips around the world.
如果我中了彩票，我会买两张环游世界的机票。
If you buy me a ticket, I'll go with you for sure.
如果你给我买张票，我肯定跟你去。
My dad would freak out if I even mention a trip like that.
如果我提这样的旅行，我爸爸会吓疯的。
All right.
好了。
This is a good one.
这个问题不错。
What would your mom say if you told her that you're going to get married?
如果你告诉你妈妈你要结婚了，她会说什么？
If I told her that, she would faint and have me committed.
如果我告诉她，她会晕倒，然后把我送进精神病院。
All right.
好了。
So, I think that was clear and well, a very common situation to teenage girls talking
所以，我认为这很清楚，而且，这是青少年女孩之间非常常见的对话场景，
to each other about, you know, boys and what would you do and da-da-da.
谈论男孩、你会怎么做等等。
Guys do this too.
男生也会这样。
So, don't just put this on the girls, okay?
所以，别只把这事归到女生头上，好吗？
I don't think we do it like this though.
不过我觉得我们不会这样聊。
No, but it's actually a very popular game in the car to play.
不，但这其实是在车里玩的一个很流行的游戏。
The what if game.
“如果”游戏。
Yeah.
是的。
Exactly.
没错。
And that's exactly the topic that we want to talk about today is the structure what
这正是我们今天想讨论的话题，就是“what if”这个结构，
if which is actually called a conditional.
它实际上被称为条件句。
All right.
好的。
It's called a conditional because the results, the thing that happens depends on something
它被称为条件句，因为结果，也就是发生的事情，取决于其他
else.
事情。
Exactly.
没错。
So, let's actually take a look at the words in today's language takeaway before we talk
那么，在我们讨论这些语法内容之前，先来看看今天“语言要点”中的单词。
about all this grammar stuff.
语言要点。
Language takeaway.
Okay.
好的。
So, we'll start out with some basic words.
我们先从一些基本词汇开始。
Well, you know, they were talking about guys and she said if Eric asked you out.
嗯，你知道，她们在谈论男生，她说“if Eric asked you out”。
Right?
对吧？
So, to ask somebody out.
所以，“to ask somebody out”。
Okay, so this might be a little bit strange because you think, okay, to ask is to ask
好的，这可能有点奇怪，因为你会想，“ask”是问问题。
a question.
问问题。
But to ask out, it's a fixed phrase.
但“ask out”是一个固定短语。
It's something you say, these two words go together, right?
这两个词是连在一起用的，对吧？
So, I want to ask someone out, that means I want to invite someone on a date.
所以，“I want to ask someone out”意思是我想邀请某人约会。
On a romantic date, usually.
通常是浪漫的约会。
So, yeah.
所以，是的。
I want to ask him out to dinner or he asked me out to the movies.
我想约他出去吃饭，或者他约我去看电影。
Now, if I didn't want to ask somebody out on a romantic date, what verb would you use?
如果我不想约某人出去进行浪漫约会，你会用什么动词？
I'd say you could invite someone out.
我会说你可以用“invite someone out”。
But then again, it's always a little bit, well, you can say invite for someone if you're
但话说回来，这总是有点，嗯，如果你要邀请他们约会，你也可以说“invite”。
going to ask them on a date too.
也可以。
So, I'd say to ask out is always romantic and to invite can be romantic or just friends.
所以，我认为“ask out”总是浪漫的，而“invite”可以是浪漫的，也可以只是朋友之间。
Okay.
好的。
So, to ask somebody out.
所以，“to ask somebody out”。
Now, they were talking about other situations, maybe they would go on a trip or something
现在，她们还讨论了其他情况，也许她们会去旅行之类的，
and she said my dad would freak out.
她说“my dad would freak out”。
This is a great phrase, this is something that I used a lot when I was a teenager.
这是一个很棒的短语，我十几岁的时候经常用。
The word freak out?
“freak out”这个词？
Freak out.
吓疯。
So, the verb to freak out means to be really angry or upset or, you know, it could be a
所以，动词“to freak out”意思是真的很生气或心烦意乱，或者，你知道，它可以是
good thing or a bad thing.
好事或坏事。
But usually, when we're talking about our parents, it's a bad thing.
但通常，当我们谈论父母时，是坏事。
It's a bad thing.
是坏事。
So, they get angry, they start yelling at you.
所以，他们会生气，开始对你大喊大叫。
Yeah.
是的。
So, freak out means like overreact.
所以，“freak out”意思是反应过度。
All right.
好的。
The last word that we have in language takeaway today is committed.
今天“语言要点”中的最后一个词是“committed”。
Well let's look at the whole phrase.
我们来看看整个短语。
He says she would have me committed.
他说“she would have me committed”。
So, this is actually being done to someone.
所以，这实际上是别人对某人做的事情。
Now, we did look at this word before but basically for marriage, right?
我们之前确实看过这个词，但基本上是关于婚姻的，对吧？
To commit to somebody, to promise.
对某人做出承诺，保证。
Yeah, but to have someone committed means that you're going to send them away to maybe
是的，但“to have someone committed”意思是你要把他们送走，可能是
a mental institution.
送到精神病院。
Exactly.
没错。
So, this means they have psychological problems and someone else sends them to the hospital
所以，这意味着他们有心理问题，别人把他们送到医院，
because they can't send themselves.
因为他们自己不能去。
Exactly.
没错。
So, it's always used to have someone committed, right?
所以，它总是用于“to have someone committed”，对吧？
Right, because it's being done to them.
对，因为这是别人对他们做的事情。
They don't want it to happen.
他们不希望它发生。
It's involuntary.
这是非自愿的。
Okay.
好的。
So, she had him committed.
所以，她把他送进了精神病院。
My mom's going to have me committed if I keep working 20 hours a day.
如果我每天工作20个小时，我妈妈会把我送进精神病院的。
Exactly.
没错。
So, that's the way you use it.
所以，这就是它的用法。
So, now you have another way of using this verb.
现在，你有了这个动词的另一种用法。
But now I think we should listen to this dialogue again.
但现在我认为我们应该再听一遍这段对话。
We're going to slow it down a little bit and then we'll come back and look at this grammar
我们会放慢一点速度，然后回来看看我们想讨论的
focus that we want to talk about.
语法重点。
Okay, next question.
好的，下一个问题。
If Eric asked you out on a date, what would you say?
如果 Eric 约你出去约会，你会怎么说？
Duh, I would say yes.
那还用说，我会说好。
Eric is the most popular kid in school.
Eric 是学校里最受欢迎的孩子。
Okay, my turn.
好的，轮到我了。
What would you do if you won the lottery?
如果你中了彩票，你会做什么？
Let's see.
让我想想。
If I won the lottery, I would buy two tickets for a trip around the world.
如果我中了彩票，我会买两张环游世界的机票。
If you buy me a ticket, I will go with you for sure.
如果你给我买张票，我肯定跟你去。
My dad would freak out if I even mention a trip like that.
如果我提这样的旅行，我爸爸会吓疯的。
Alright, this is a good one.
好了，这个问题不错。
What would your mom say if you told her you were going to get married?
如果你告诉你妈妈你要结婚了，她会说什么？
If I told her that, she would faint and have me committed.
如果我告诉她，她会晕倒，然后把我送进精神病院。
Alright, so we understood all the vocab now.
好了，现在我们理解了所有词汇。
Now let's take a look at these unreal situations and what we were saying, the what if game.
现在让我们看看这些不真实的情况，以及我们所说的“如果”游戏。
Right, so I think it's important to push these into two different categories, right?
对，所以我认为把它们分成两类很重要，对吧？
We have one kind where it's very unrealistic, it's probably not going to happen, that kind
有一种是非常不现实的，可能不会发生，
of situation.
那种情况。
And the other one is a situation that could very well happen, something that's probably
另一种是很有可能发生的情况，可能是非常常见的，
very common, okay?
好吗？
So the first one we're going to talk about is very unrealistic situations, things that
所以，我们要讨论的第一种是非常不现实的情况，那些可能
probably won't happen.
不会发生的事情。
Okay, so let's take a look at an example that we found in the dialogue.
好的，让我们看看对话中的一个例子。
The most common one and I think everybody gets asked this question is, if you won the
最常见的一个，我认为每个人都被问过这个问题，就是“如果你中了彩票，
lottery, what would you do?
你会做什么？”
Okay, if you won the lottery.
好的，“if you won the lottery”。
So this is a situation that's very uncommon, right?
所以，这是一种非常罕见的情况，对吧？
Not many people win the lottery.
没多少人中彩票。
So we have to say, if you won the lottery, so we use this verb in the past tense.
所以，我们必须说“if you won the lottery”，所以我们用过去时态的这个动词。
If you won the lottery, if this happened, what would you do?
“If you won the lottery”，如果这发生了，“what would you do？”
Right.
对。
So, Catherine, if you won the lottery, what would you do?
那么，Catherine，如果你中了彩票，你会做什么？
If I won the lottery, I would buy a boat and sail around the world with my friends.
如果我中了彩票，我会买一艘船，和朋友们一起环游世界。
Alright, so another example, again, using the same structure, right?
好的，另一个例子，再次使用相同的结构，对吧？
The verb in the simple past tense, we would say, if you were stuck on an island with one
动词用一般过去时，我们会说，“if you were stuck on an island with one
other person, who would that be?
other person, who would that be？”
Alright, so if you were stuck on a desert island with one person, who would that person
好的，所以，“if you were stuck on a desert island with one person, who would that person
be?
be？”
So Marco, I'm going to ask you, who would it be?
那么，Marco，我要问你，那个人会是谁？
I think it would be an engineer or a scientist that could probably get me off the island.
我认为会是一个工程师或科学家，也许能带我离开那个岛。
What about your girlfriend?
那你女朋友呢？
No, no, well, you know, that's the point, if I can get to her quicker.
不，不，嗯，你知道，重点是，如果我能更快地找到她。
Okay.
好的。
I would say maybe kind of romantic, but kind of not.
我会说可能有点浪漫，但又不完全是。
So that's the first situation.
所以，这是第一种情况。
We've got these situations like being stuck on an island, winning the lottery.
我们有像被困在岛上、中彩票这样的情况。
These are very unlikely.
这些都非常不可能。
But what about the other kind?
但另一种情况呢？
But before we move on to that, you notice that we use the verb was, we didn't say, if
但在我们继续之前，你注意到我们用了动词“was”，我们没有说“if
I was on an island, I said, if I were, right?
I was on an island”，我说了“if I were”，对吧？
Or if you were.
或者“if you were”。
So this is the way that you use it in these conditionals.
所以，这就是你在这些条件句中的用法。
If I were you, or if you were president of the United States.
“If I were you”，或者“if you were president of the United States”。
Yeah, this is a rule.
是的，这是一个规则。
So this is a grammar rule.
所以，这是一个语法规则。
We're not going to describe why it happens because it's very, very complicated.
我们不打算解释为什么会这样，因为它非常非常复杂。
And you can look it up on our site.
你可以在我们的网站上查一下。
But we're going to describe how to use it.
但我们要解释如何使用它。
That's the most important.
那是最重要的。
So we can say, for example, Marco, if I were you, I would dye my hair red.
所以，我们可以说，例如，Marco，“if I were you, I would dye my hair red”。
Why?
为什么？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I think it would look cool.
我觉得那样会看起来很酷。
I don't think so.
我不这么认为。
So if I were you, I would.
所以，“if I were you, I would”。
Or if you were me, what would you do?
或者“if you were me, what would you do？”
Exactly.
没错。
So we always use it like this, right?
所以，我们总是这样用，对吧？
If you're going to use this conditional, always use were for the subject.
如果你要用这个条件句，主语后面总是用“were”。
Never was.
永远不要用“was”。
Right.
对。
So you can tell.
所以，你可以看出来。
This is a very, very big grammar issue.
这是一个非常非常大的语法问题。
A lot of English speakers make this mistake.
很多英语母语者都会犯这个错误。
Yes, very many.
是的，非常多。
But now you know that you shouldn't make this mistake and you can speak properly.
但现在你知道你不应该犯这个错误，你可以说得更规范。
All right, so now that we've seen these semi-unreal situations, let's move on to something that's
好了，现在我们看完了这些半真实的情况，让我们继续讨论一些
a little bit more probable, that it may happen.
更可能发生、可能会发生的事情。
Right.
对。
So we've got these situations that are common or likely.
所以，我们有这些常见或可能的情况。
For example, in this lesson we hear, I will go with you for sure.
例如，在这节课中，我们听到“I will go with you for sure”。
So this is, if you buy me a ticket to travel, of course I will go with you.
所以，这是“if you buy me a ticket to travel, of course I will go with you”。
So if you buy, this is in the present tense, if you buy, then I will.
所以，“if you buy”，这是现在时态，“if you buy, then I will”。
Right.
对。
So now you notice the difference.
所以，现在你注意到区别了。
The verb is in the present and then we use, instead of would, we use will.
动词是现在时，然后我们不用“would”，而用“will”。
So again, I can say, if it rains tomorrow, I will stay home and watch TV all day.
所以，我再说一遍，“if it rains tomorrow, I will stay home and watch TV all day”。
Okay, so think about this.
好的，想想这个。
Before we talked about going to desert islands, now we're talking about rain and the weather.
之前我们谈论去荒岛，现在我们谈论下雨和天气。
They're very, very different.
它们非常非常不同。
The rain is, you know, it's very common.
这雨吧，你知道，挺常见的。
So we can say, if it rains tomorrow, I will need an umbrella.
所以我们可以说，如果明天下雨，我就需要一把伞。
What about this?
那这个呢？
If we have lunch tomorrow, what will we eat?
如果我们明天一起吃午饭，我们会吃什么？
Okay, so we have lunch pretty much every day, right?
好吧，我们几乎每天都一起吃午饭，对吧？
Yeah, pretty much.
是啊，差不多。
So again, it's a situation that is very probable.
所以再说一次，这是一个非常可能发生的情况。
So if we have lunch tomorrow, we will probably eat, I don't know, pasta, I think.
所以如果我们明天一起吃午饭，我们可能会吃，嗯，我想是意大利面吧。
I'm feeling like pasta.
我想吃意大利面。
Pasta, noodles.
意大利面，面条。
Yeah.
嗯。
All right, so Marco, let's take another listen to some of these phrases and try and figure
好了，马可，我们再听一遍这些短语，试着在听的时候分辨一下，这是哪种条件句，第一类还是第二类。
out while you're listening, which kind of conditional it is, first or the second.
Example one.
例子一。
If it's sunny today, we will go to the park.
如果今天天气晴朗，我们就去公园。
Example two.
例子二。
I would get a divorce if I were you.
如果我是你，我会离婚。
Example three.
例子三。
Mary will be very sad if Joe leaves.
如果乔离开，玛丽会非常难过。
Example four.
例子四。
We wouldn't be so late if Nick drove faster.
如果尼克开快一点，我们就不会这么晚了。
Very good.
非常好。
So we have two different examples and the first conditional is the one that we mentioned
所以我们有两个不同的例子，第一条件句是我们提到的非常可能发生的情况，第二条件句是不太可能发生的情况。
is very probable and the second conditional is the one that's not so probable.
So they're very easy to distinguish.
它们很容易区分。
You don't really need to know the names, just know how to use them, right?
你其实不需要知道名字，只要知道怎么用就行，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
And so just remember, if you were me, what would you do?
所以只要记住，如果你是我，你会怎么做？
We've got these kind of pairs, these words that go together.
我们有这些成对的词，这些搭配在一起的词。
And the other one is more common.
另一个更常见。
If it rains tomorrow, I will bring an umbrella.
如果明天下雨，我会带伞。
Perfect.
完美。
So why don't we listen to this dialogue for the last time just to kind of reinforce everything
那我们最后再听一遍这段对话，巩固一下所有内容，然后我们再回来多聊一会儿。
and then we'll come back and talk a little bit more.
Okay next question.
好了，下一个问题。
If Eric asked you out on a date, what would you say?
如果埃里克约你出去，你会怎么说？
Duh, I would say yes.
那还用说，我会说好。
Eric is the most popular kid in school.
埃里克是学校里最受欢迎的孩子。
Okay, my turn.
好了，轮到我了。
What would you do if you won the lottery?
如果你中了彩票，你会做什么？
Let's see.
让我想想。
If I won the lottery, I would buy two tickets for trips around the world.
如果我中了彩票，我会买两张环球旅行的票。
If you buy me a ticket, I'll go with you for sure.
如果你给我买张票，我肯定跟你去。
My dad would freak out if I even mention a trip like that.
我要是提这样的旅行，我爸会吓疯的。
All right, this is a good one.
好了，这是个好问题。
What would your mom say if you told her that you're going to get married?
如果你告诉你妈妈你要结婚了，她会说什么？
If I told her that, she would faint and have me committed.
如果我告诉她，她会晕倒，然后把我送进精神病院。
So Marco, if we talk any more about grammar, someone's going to have to have me committed.
所以马可，如果我们再谈语法，就有人得把我送进精神病院了。
It is a little bit difficult to talk about grammar, especially on a podcast because it's
谈语法确实有点难，尤其是在播客上，因为这是个很难的话题，而且也挺沉重的，对吧？
such a difficult topic and it's also kind of heavy, right?
It is, but I'll tell you this.
是的，但我告诉你。
These are very, very common phrases.
这些都是非常非常常见的短语。
People use these all the time.
人们经常用这些。
We talk in hypotheticals very often.
我们经常谈论假设的情况。
So if you're asking for advice, for example, or if you're just playing a game in the car,
所以如果你在征求意见，比如，或者只是在车里玩游戏，你都会遇到这些，能够知道怎么用它们非常重要。
you're going to encounter these and it's very important to be able to know how to use them.
So, and this is what we want to see now.
所以，这就是我们现在想看到的。
Please come to our website at EnglishPod.com and you have a million questions.
请来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，那里有无数的问题。
You have a million hypotheticals that you can leave on our website.
你可以在我们的网站上留下无数个假设性问题。
So let us know.
所以告诉我们吧。
Ask us the craziest, funniest, weirdest questions that you can, right?
问我们你能想到的最疯狂、最有趣、最奇怪的问题，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
And if you have questions about the stuff that we've been talking about, you're not
如果你对我们刚才讲的内容有疑问，或者有些地方不太清楚，尽管问我们，因为我们很乐意回答你的问题，并在网站上提供更多例子。
really clear on some things, just ask us because we're happy to answer your questions and give
more examples on the website.
All right, so we'll see you guys there and until next time.
好了，那我们就在那里见你们，下次再见。
Bye, everyone.
大家再见。
Bye.
再见。
EnglishPod at www.engvid.com
EnglishPod 在 www.engvid.com